Guide to the Frances Eikel Whittaker Palmer Weed Papers, 1912-1975 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Frances Eikel Whittaker Palmer Weed papers 1912-1975 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Weed, Frances Eikel Whittaker Palmer.
1.2 linear feet Extent: 293 Items
Government employee and North Carolina resident. Collection consists primarily of correspondence to Mrs. Weed. She graduated from the University of Texas, worked as a secretary for the government, and the Texas Gulf Sulphur Company and served in the military during WWII. She settled with her second husband in Asheville, NC. Other items include legal documents, stock reports, tax statements, clippings, school report cards, church programs, pictures, photo albums, and three volumes of memorabilia from the school days of her children.
RL.02013
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Frances Eikel Whittaker Palmer Weed Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1980.
Collection Overview
Collection consists primarily of correspondence to Mrs. Weed. She graduated from the University of Texas, worked as a secretary for the government, and the Texas Gulf Sulphur Company and served in the military during World War II. She settled with her second husband in Asheville, N.C. Other items include legal documents, stock reports, tax statements, clippings, school report cards, church programs, pictures, photo albums, and three volumes of memorabilia from the school days of her children.
Subject Headings
Texas Gulf Sulphur Company, Inc; University of Texas at Austin -- Alumni and alumnae; United States Government employees; World War, 1939-1945
Contents of Collection
- Frances Eikel Whittaker Palmer Weed Papers, 1912-1975 and undated, (3 boxes)
  The bulk of the correspondence in Box 1 ranges from 1960 to 1961. Miscellaneous folder in Box 2 contains grades, event programs, and writings by others. Yearbook in Box 3 is The Cricket from Seguin High School. Poem notebook in Box 3 is that of Josie Whittaker and contains both original poems and copies of others.
  - Correspondence, 1912-1975 and undated (Box 1)
  - Legal papers (Box 2)
  - Financial papers (Box 2)
  - Writings (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2)
  - Printed materials (Box 2)
  - Photographs, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Picture album, 1927-1930 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1920-1921 (Box 3)
  - Yearbook, 1920-1921 (Box 3)
  - Poem notebook, 1919 (Box 3)